YWCA of the U.S.A. Records. Record Group 6. Program: Series I. Departmant, Staff, and Committees
Sophia Smith Collection
- SERIES I. DEPARTMENT, STAFF, AND COMMITTEES
  - Publications and Resource Materials
    - Series/Serials
      - Child Care Network News and Action Alert, 1988-89 (Box 354, Folder 9)
      - Program Services newsletter, Jun 1987-Apr 1988 (Box 354, Folder 10)
      - Program Services Bulletin, Apr 1988- Jan(?) 1992 (Box 354, Folder 11-13)
  - Reports
    - Home/Method/Research and Method Department 1908-23
      - Department, Chair, and Executive Secretary, 1907-14, 1919-20 (Box 354, Folder 14-16)
      - Committee annual
        - Association Extension/Town Committee, 1909-12 (Box 354, Folder 17)
        - City Committee, 1911-12 (Box 354, Folder 18)
        - Student Committee, 1910-11 (Box 354, Folder 19)
      - Convention reports, 1911, 1920 (Box 355, Folder 1)
      - Architect reports (Julia Morgan, William F. Thompson), 1918-19 (Box 355, Folder 2)
      - Miscellaneous, 1918-20, n.d. (Box 355, Folder 3)
      - Secretary annual, biennial, and periodic
        - Margaret Alton, 1920 (Box 355, Folder 4)
        - Elizabeth Anselm, 1918-19 (Box 355, Folder 5)
        - Vera Barger, 1919 (Box 355, Folder 6)
        - Helen F. Barnes, 1908 (Box 355, Folder 7)
        - Alida J. Bigelow, 1920 (Box 355, Folder 8)
        - Crystal Bird, 1918-19 (Box 355, Folder 9)
        - Leslie Blanchard, 1913-20 (Box 355, Folder 10)
        - Marion Griswold Boalt, 1919-20 (employment) (Box 355, Folder 11)
        - Elizabeth Boies, 1911-16 (Box 355, Folder 12)
        - Dorothy Dulles [Bourne], 1917-19 (Box 355, Folder 13)
        - Eva D. Bowles, 1913-21 (Box 355, Folder 14)
        - Edith Terry Bremer, 1913-17 (Box 355, Folder 15)
        - Rachel Brooks, 1917-20 (Box 355, Folder 16)
        - Anna L. Brown, 1911-20 (Box 355, Folder 17)
        - Etha Louise Buchanan, 1918-20 (Box 355, Folder 18)
        - Alice Standish Buell, 1920 (Box 355, Folder 19)
        - Oolooah Burner, 1911-21 (Box 355, Folder 20)
        - Margaret Burton, 1913-18 (Box 355, Folder 21)
        - Eliza R. Butler, 1913-17 (Box 355, Folder 22)
        - Mary L. Cady, 1918-20 (Box 355, Folder 23)
        - Anna M. Clark, 1920 (Box 355, Folder 24)
        - Jessie Clark, 1921 (employment) (Box 355, Folder 25)
        - Bertha Conde, 1913-18 (Box 355, Folder 26)
        - Ethel Cutler, 1912-21 (Box 355, Folder 27)
        - Edith M. Dabb, 1913-20 (Box 355, Folder 28)
        - Maud S. Davis, 1920-21 (Box 355, Folder 29)
        - Lorna Dietz, 1918-20 (Box 355, Folder 30)
        - Marcia O. Dunham, 1911-14 (Box 355, Folder 31)
        - Mabel T. Everett, 1913-15 (Box 355, Folder 32)
        - Lena M. Farrar, 1919 (Box 355, Folder 33)
        - Jessie Field, 1913-16 (Box 355, Folder 34)
        - Blanche Geary, 1910-20 (Box 355, Folder 35)
        - Katy Boyd George, 1920 (Box 355, Folder 36)
        - Katherine Gerwick, 1919-21 (Box 355, Folder 37)
        - Gertrude Gogin, 1917-21 (Box 355, Folder 38)
        - Gertrude Griffith, 1911-16 (Box 355, Folder 39)
        - Maud L. Harrison, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 1)
        - Mabel Head, 1919-21 (Box 356, Folder 2)
        - Almira F. Holmes, 1921 (Box 356, Folder 3)
        - Louise Holmquist, 1909-19 (Box 356, Folder 4-5)
        - Marion E. Hopkins, 1917-19 (Box 356, Folder 6)
        - Addie W. Hunton, 1913-14 (Box 356, Folder 7)
        - Reba J. Hurn, 1919 (Box 356, Folder 8)
        - Imogene Ireland, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 9)
        - Mary E. Jackson, 1918-20 (Box 356, Folder 10)
        - Elizabeth Jenkins, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 11)
        - Eleanor Larrabee Lattimore, 1919-22 (Box 356, Folder 12)
        - Catharine D. Lealtad, 1918 (Box 356, Folder 13)
        - Clare Lewis, 1920-21 (employment) (Box 356, Folder 14)
        - Kate Logan, 1917-18 (Box 356, Folder 15)
        - Hazel MacKaye, 1918-20 (Box 356, Folder 16)
        - Louise McMaster, 1919-22 (Box 356, Folder 17)
        - Gertrude F. Murrell, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 18)
        - Mary Musson, 1917-18 (Box 356, Folder 19)
        - Amanda C. Nelson, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 20)
        - Helen J. Owen, 1918-19 (Box 356, Folder 21)
        - Ruth Lee Pearson, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 22)
        - Lena M. Phillips, 1918-19 (Box 356, Folder 23)
        - Emma Phinney, 1918-21 (Box 356, Folder 24)
        - Josephine Pinyon, 1911-15 (Box 356, Folder 25)
        - Margaret Swain Pratt, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 26)
        - Margaret Proctor, 1917-22 (Box 356, Folder 27)
        - Anna V. Rice, 1913-21 (Box 356, Folder 28)
        - Clarinda Richards, 1918 (Box 356, Folder 29)
        - Mary E. Rust, 1920-21 (Box 356, Folder 30)
        - Anna Seaburg, 1911-20 (Box 356, Folder 31)
        - Anna G. Seesholtz, 1918 (Box 356, Folder 32)
        - Agnes Sharp, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 33)
        - Florence Simms, 1908-20 (Box 356, Folder 34)
        - Mary Sims, 1913-20 (Box 356, Folder 35)
        - Lucy R. Somerville, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 36)
        - Marie Lutters [Stanton], 1920 (Box 356, Folder 37)
        - E. Beatrice Stearns, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 38)
        - Mrs. M. C. Stevens, 1920 (Box 356, Folder 39)
        - Mabel Eleanor Stone, 1918-21 (Box 356, Folder 40)
        - Mary S. Stuart, 1918 (Box 356, Folder 41)
        - Helen L. Thomas, 1911-17 (Box 356, Folder 42)
        - Helen Peters Wallace, 1915-18 (Box 357, Folder 1)
        - Margaret Williamson, 1917-18 (Box 357, Folder 2)
        - Grace E. Willis, 1919 (Box 357, Folder 3)
        - Marie Wilson, 1913 (Box 357, Folder 4)
        - Sue Ann Wilson, 1920-21 (Box 357, Folder 5)
        - Margaret Wells Wood, 1920 (Box 357, Folder 6)
        - Bertha J. Woodward, 1920 (Box 357, Folder 7)
    - Education and Research Division1923-32
      - Biennial, 1928-31 (Box 357, Folder 8)
      - Oolooah Burner, 1922-23 (Box 357, Folder 9)
      - Margaret E. Burton, 1922-24 (Box 357, Folder 10)
      - Bertha Conde, 1923-24 (Box 357, Folder 11)
      - Maud S. Davis, 1922 (Box 357, Folder 12)
      - Grace A. Day, 1924 (Box 357, Folder 13)
      - Katharine Gerwick, 1922 (Box 357, Folder 14)
      - Almira F. Holmes, 1922-23 (Box 357, Folder 15)
      - Anna V. Rice, 1922 (Box 357, Folder 16)
      - Mabel Eleanor Stone, 1922 (Box 357, Folder 17)
    - Program Staff [post-1932]
      - Program-Planning Studies
        - Summary Report, 1931-33 (Box 357, Folder 18)
        - Report, Jan-Jun 1939 (Box 357, Folder 19)
        - Work Tool for Immediate Use, 1940 (Box 357, Folder 20)
      - "Program to Meet Changing Needs," 1945-46 (Box 357, Folder 21)
      - Report of the Committee on Program and Budget Apportionment to the National Board, 31 Jan 1950 (Box 357, Folder 22)
      - "Program in the YWCA: Findings from 150 Self-Studies of Local YWCAs," Program Study Committee, May 1951 (Box 357, Folder 23)
      - YWCA Involvement in Program under the Economic Opportunity Act of 1964 (Box 357, Folder 24)
      - Special Report on the International Consultation on Sexism in the 1970s, World Council of Churches, West Berlin, Jun 1974 (Box 357, Folder 25)
  - Studies
    - A Study of the Organization and Activities of the YWCA, circa 1919 (Box 357, Folder 26)
    - The Study of a Plan for a College Dormitory or Residence, 1931 (Box 357, Folder 27)
    - Study of Work with Younger Girls in the YWCA, 1932-34: report, [see also Series IV. Subseries D. Teenage Program] (Box 357, Folder 28)
    - Rural Life and the YWCA, 1934 (Box 357, Folder 29)
    - Study of the Standards of Work of Association Employees Other Than Professionals, 1935-36, by Elsie D. Harper (Box 357, Folder 30)
    - The General Secretary of a Community Y.W.C.A., A Job Analysis by Margaretta Brereton, 1939-40 (Box 358, Folder 1)
    - Study of Contemporary Housing Needs of Young Women Living in YWCA Residences, 1969: questionnaire only (Box 358, Folder 2)
    - Housing Questionnaire, 1971 (Box 358, Folder 3)
    - YWCA Programs Serving Battered Women and Their Children: questionnaire, 1980 (Box 358, Folder 4)
    - An Analysis of Child Care Programs in the YWCA, 1982-85 (Box 358, Folder 5)
  - Training
    - "A Program Workshop: Suggested Guide for Leaders," n.d. (1950s) (Box 358, Folder 6)
    - Workshop on Program, Nov 1953 (Box 358, Folder 7)
    - Seminar for Experienced YWCA Staff, Aug-Sep 1954 (Box 358, Folder 8)
    - Workshop on Program Development, Mar 1959 (Box 358, Folder 9)
  - Miscellaneous
    - Buildings scrapbooks [disassembled]
      - YWCA buildings
        - A-L (Box 358, Folder 10-15)
        - M-Z (Box 359, Folder 1-5)
      - Non-YWCA buildings, A-Z (Box 359, Folder 6-14)